<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader><!-- I can't seem to figure out what tags i should create to be able to place a handDesc or handNote element in. -->
              <!-- I keep running into dead ends when backtracking what tree of elements to include before incerting the hand elements -->
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Irvin Letter</title>
            <!-- Title -->
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Publication Information</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <repository></repository>
               </msIdentifier>
            </msDesc>
            <!--  <p> From the PSU Behrend Archives. A letter made from Irvin Kochel to Mary Behrendin
               1955. </p>-->
            <!-- Information about the source -->
         </sourceDesc>
         
         
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>


   <text>
      <body>
         <head><l><date when="1955-06-13">June 13, 1955</date></l>
            <l><name>Mrs. <reg>Mary B. Behrend</reg></name></l>
            <address>
               <street>21 West Putnam Avenue</street>
               <name type="city">Greenwich, </name>
               <region>Conn.</region>
            </address>
         </head>
         <p>Dear <rs type="person">Mrs. Behrend:</rs><lb/> In reference to your recent letters, I
            offer he following comments--</p>
         <lb/>
         <p n="1">We would be most pleased to have <rs type="person">Mr. Paul Laver</rs> from the
            Cemetery do certain <lb/> planting around the entrance to the <rs type="plac">Behrend
               Center</rs> campus. We understand <lb/> that this planting will be done by utilising
            the existing shrubbery in the <lb/> formal gardens. It is also my understanding that you
            will remimburse <name>Mr Laven</name><lb/> for his labors only for the planting around
            the enterance and for no other plant<pc force="inter">-</pc><lb/> ing. If you have not
            not already done so, I would suggest that you contact <rs type="person">Mr.
            Day</rs><lb/> informing him of your desires to have <name>Mr. Laver</name> do the above
            mentioned work.<lb/></p>
         <p n="2">Insofar as the new building is concerned, we do not plan ot proceed with this<lb/>
            project this year. We have not as yet heard from <rs type="org">General Electric</rs> as
            to their <lb/> intention of us doing their training program this fall. It will be
            impossible at <lb/> this late date to complete any building arrangemants for the Fall
            term, con<pc force="inter">-</pc><lb/> sequently we have delayed any action on a new
            building of this present year. <lb/> We, however, plan to spend approximatly $25,000.00
            completing the other <lb/> half of the barn for utilization as classrooms.<lb/></p>
         <p n="3">We have located some of the lights for the living room which are in need of
            repair.<lb/> At the present time we will investigate the repair of these lights and I
            will re<pc force="inter">-</pc><lb/> port to you at a later date as to whether or not
            they can be effectively repaired.<lb/>
         </p>
         <p n="4">We are making arrangements to erect a wrought iron rail around the case in
            which<lb/> the <name type="place">Niagara</name> is desplayed. Quite a few people have
            commented about the ship and <lb/> have visited us with the express purpose of viewing
            it.<lb/></p>
         <p n="5">Under separate cover we are sending you the television films of the
            presentation<lb/> of the Flagship. These films can be shown on a standard
               <measure>16mm</measure>. projector.<lb/>
         </p>
         <p n="6">In reference to the heating of the swimming pool, I have talked on two
            different<lb/> occasions with <name type="person">Mr. Scobell</name> about completing
            the project. As yet he has done <lb/> nothing to heat the pool with the exception of
            having ordered a piece of equip<pc force="inter">-</pc><lb/> ment that is needed to put
            the furnace in the immediate future to complete it.<lb/></p>
         <p n="7">In reference to the scholarships, as a result of our last <orgName>Advisory
               Board</orgName> meeting,<lb/> Mr. Nick appointed a new <orgName>Scholarship
               Committee</orgName>, consisting of <rs type="person">Jerry Stokes</rs>, Chair-<lb/>
            man, <rs type="person">William Hamilton </rs>and <rs type="person">John Zern</rs>. I
            have had one meeting with <name>Mr. Stokes </name>and <lb/> we are planning to arrange
            for a number of scholarships which will be available <lb/> by <date>September
               1956</date>. Our scholarship fund at present has been consumed so that <lb/> there is
            only $650.00 remaining in this fund. We have given one scholarship <lb/> to a <name
               type="place">McDowell High School </name>student for <date>September 1955</date>. The
            scholarship fund <lb/> has not been generally advertised this year because of the small
            amount of <lb/> money available. We have not in the past had scholarships that were
            specifically <lb/> designated as <orgName>Protestant scholarships</orgName>. Inasmuch as
            we are a state university<lb/> we do not feel that it would be ethical to differentiate
            as to religion or <lb/> race in the issuance of a scholarship. I will keep you informed
            of the activities <lb/> of this committee and what prograss they make. I am quite sure
            that we will be<lb/> building the scholarship fund to the point where at least one
            scholarship will<lb/> be available to all eleven of the area high schools each year.
            Generally speak<pc force="inter">-</pc><lb/> ing scholarships are in the amount of
            $100.00 per year, per student.<lb/></p>
         <p n="8"><rs type="person">Ross P. Wright </rs>of <orgName>Reed Mfg. Company </orgName>has
            sent several copies of letters that<lb/> were supposedly written by <rs type="person"
               >Commodore Perry </rs>on the deck of the <name type="place">Ship Niagara </name>on
            <lb/> the afternoon of his victory. We plan to have these copies framed and placed <lb/>
            in <name type="place">Erie Hall </name>along with the Flagship.<lb/></p>
         <p n="9">I hope this letter finds you in good health and enjoying the summer. Please<lb/>
            give my kindest regards to <rs type="person">Gail</rs>. Our family is well and in good
            health.<lb/>
         </p>
         <closer><salute>Cordially yours, </salute>
            <space/>
            <signed>Irvin H.Kochel</signed>
            <roleName>Administrative Head</roleName>
            <space/> P.S. Thanks very much for the London Illustrated News. We will put these to
            good use in the Library at Behrend Center. </closer>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
